Your senses will never be the same.
Tommy is a drama, music film directed by Ken Russell.
After a series of traumatic childhood events, a psychosomatically deaf, dumb and blind
boy becomes a master pinball player and the object of a religious cult.
Frank, played by Oliver Reed.
Nora, played by Ann-Margret.
Tommy, played by Roger Daltrey.
The Pinball Wizard, played by Elton John.
The Preacher, played by Eric Clapton.
Himself, played by John Entwistle.
Tommy is a 1975 British musical fantasy drama film written, co-produced, and directed by Ken Russell, based on the Who's 1969 rock
opera album about a psychosomatically deaf, mute, and blind boy who becomes a pinball champion and religious leader.
The film featured an ensemble cast, including the members of the Who themselves (most notably, lead singer Roger Daltrey, who plays
the title role), Oliver Reed, Ann-Margret, Elton John, Eric Clapton, Jack Nicholson, Robert Powell and Tina Turner.
An independent production by Russell and Robert Stigwood, Tommy was released in the United States on 19 March
1975 by Columbia Pictures and in the United Kingdom on 26 March 1975 by Hemdale Film Corporation.
The film was shown at the 1975 Cannes Film Festival, but
was not entered into the main competition.
Ann-Margret received a Golden Globe Award for her performance and was
also nominated for the Academy Award for Best Actress.
Pete Townshend was also nominated for an Oscar for his work in
scoring and adapting the music for the film.
In 1975, the film won the award for Rock Movie of the
Year in the First Annual Rock Music Awards.
The film explores themes of adultery, child abuse,
1970s, christmas party, deaf-mute.
The tone is emotional and mind_bending.